[
    {
        "question": "Gif mon his mete etan (<em>willan</em>) #### — If someone does not want to eat his foot",
        "correctAnswer": "nyle",
        "explanation": "Here 'willan' is in the negated third person singular present form '<em>nyle</em>' because the subject is 'mon'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Seo cwen urum wordum and gewritum hieran (<em>willan</em>) #### — The queen does not want to hear our words and writings",
        "correctAnswer": "nyle",
        "explanation": "Here 'willan' is in the negated third person singular present form '<em>nyle</em>' because the subject is 'seo cwen'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðu (<em>willan</em>) #### to minum gode þe gebiddan — You do not want to worship my gods",
        "correctAnswer": "nylt",
        "explanation": "Here 'willan' is in the negated second person singular present form '<em>nylt</em>' because the subject is 'Ðu'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic wæs on cearcerne, and ge min (<em>willan</em>) #### fandian — I was incarcerated, and ye didn't want to find me",
        "correctAnswer": "noldon",
        "explanation": "Here 'willan' is in the negated plural past form '<em>noldon</em>' because the subject is 'ge'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Seo fæmne (<em>willan</em>) #### him andswarigen nan word — The woman did not want to answer him with any words",
        "correctAnswer": "nolde",
        "explanation": "Here 'willan' is in the negated third person singular past form '<em>nolde</em>' because the subject is 'Seo fæmne'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie hine heton þæt flæsc etan and he hit etan (<em>willan</em>) #### — They ordered him to eat that flesh, and he didn't want to eat it",
        "correctAnswer": "nolde",
        "explanation": "Here 'willan' is in the negated third person singular past form '<em>nolde</em>' because the subject is 'he'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "He (<em>habban</em>) #### nænige stowe, þæt he mihte to gan — He didn't have any place that he could go to",
        "correctAnswer": "næfde",
        "explanation": "Here 'habban' is in the negated third person singular past form '<em>næfde</em>' because the subject is 'He'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða men þa þe on woh lifiaþ, (<em>habban</em>) #### hie na Crist on heora heortan — Those men who live in wickedness do not have Christ in their hearts",
        "correctAnswer": "nabbaþ",
        "explanation": "Here 'habban' is in the negated plural present form '<em>nabbaþ</em>' because the subject is 'Ða men'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðæt gast (<em>habban</em>) #### flæsc ond ban — The ghost does not have flesh and bone",
        "correctAnswer": "næfþ|næfð",
        "explanation": "Here 'habban' is in the negated third person singular present form '<em>næfþ</em>' because the subject is 'Ðæt gast'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie win (<em>habban</em>) #### — They did not have wine",
        "correctAnswer": "næfdon",
        "explanation": "Here 'habban' is in the negated plural past form '<em>næfdon</em>' because the subject is 'Hie'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hwæt hæfst ðu, gif ðu me (<em>habban</em>) ####? — What do you have, if you don't have me?",
        "correctAnswer": "næfst",
        "explanation": "Here 'habban' is in the negated second person singular present form '<em>næfst</em>' because the subject is 'ðu'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ic (<em>wesan</em>) #### freoh — I am not free",
        "correctAnswer": "neom",
        "explanation": "Here 'wesan' is in the negated first person singular present form '<em>neom</em>' because the subject is 'Ic'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðu (<em>wesan</em>) #### dysig, ac þin bearn is dysig — You aren't foolish, but your child is foolish",
        "correctAnswer": "neart",
        "explanation": "Here 'wesan' is in the negated second person singular present form '<em>neart</em>' because the subject is 'Ðu'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se monandæg (<em>wesan</em>) #### na fyrmest daga on þære wucan: ac is se oþer — Monday is not the first day in the week, but it is the second",
        "correctAnswer": "nis",
        "explanation": "Here 'wesan' is in the negated third person singular present form '<em>nis</em>' because the subject is 'monandæg'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hit (<em>wesan</em>) #### alyfed! — It is not allowed!",
        "correctAnswer": "nis",
        "explanation": "Here 'wesan' is in the negated third person singular present form '<em>nis</em>' because the subject is 'Hit'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðæt næfre nan man to nanum deofulgilde ne gebidde, (<em>wesan</em>) #### to nanum deadum stane ne to nanum dumbum treowe — That no man ever pray to any devil image, nor to any dead stone, nor to any dumb tree",
        "correctAnswer": "nis",
        "explanation": "Here 'wesan' is in the negated third person singular present form '<em>nis</em>' because the subject is 'man'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "(<em>wesan</em>) #### nan ðing wyrse, ðonne druncenscipe — There is nothing worse than drunkeness",
        "correctAnswer": "nis",
        "explanation": "Here 'wesan' is in the negated third person singular present form '<em>nis</em>' because the subject is 'nan ðing'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Wære ðu todæg on huntnoþe? Ic (<em>wesan</em>) #### — Were you hunting today? I was not",
        "correctAnswer": "næs",
        "explanation": "Here 'wesan' is in the negated first person singular past form '<em>næs</em>' because the subject is 'ic'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Hie wiscaþ ðæt hie næfre (<em>wesan</em>) #### acennede — They wished that they had never been born",
        "correctAnswer": "næron",
        "explanation": "Here 'wesan' is in the negated plural past form '<em>næron</em>' because the subject is 'hie'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Eall þes middaneard (<em>wesan</em>) #### þe mare dryges landes — In all this middle earth there was not a drier land",
        "correctAnswer": "næs",
        "explanation": "Here 'wesan' is in the negated third person singular past form '<em>næs</em>'",
        "commonMistakes": []
    }
]